Leah: Lean project management focusses
on ‘value’ delivery in project
management terms from the customers
perspective by cutting down on
‘waste’ whilst optimising efficiency
therefore delivering more with less.
Whereas traditional project management
is structured in stages, lean project
management enables teams to deliver
faster by managing workflow more
efficiently with continuous improvement.
It means working to deliver
what the client needs rather
than just what they asked for.
Jack: Lean project managers identify
objectives, requirements, deliverables
and acceptance criteria and the value is
what the client is willing to pay for.
Anything not focussed on solving the
problem is seen as wasted resources.
Cutting out wasted resources can have
a positive effect on delivery time and
therefore time spent on the project.
It can also help to create
continuous workflow.
Leah: A key instrument in
Lean Project Management is the
Plan-Do-Check-Act cycle [PDCA].
This is a four-stage method that
includes solutions testing, analysing
results, and improving the process
to enable teams to avoid recurring
mistakes and improve operations.
It is a good way of establishing
a culture of solutions testing
on a smaller scale which in turn
minimises potential for reworking.
The goal is to plan, execute and test
a potential solution and then analyse
the results from a client’s perspective.